Welcome to Westeros,
where the fight for the kingdom is on.
- Anyone can die.
- Which is fine.
Where great families live
and die for the Iron Throne.
They're all weaving these tangled webs.
Some are noble.
Jon Snow's everybody's hero.
Some are not.
- If you're gonna be bad, be really bad.
- I want my crown!
So many kings and queens in waiting.
It's about power and greed.
But an icy foe may well end them all.
When's it start?
Season seven is coming
and so are the dragons.
So let's burn through
the epic saga to date.
This is what Game of Thrones does, it...
- it sucks you in.
- With Game of Thrones: The Story So Far.
When you play the Game of
Thrones you win or you die.
There is no middle ground.
- Synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -
As season one opens, it's
the calm before the storm.
King Robert Baratheon rules
from the capital King's Landing
but his days are numbered.
To be king in Westeros, you sit on
the Iron Throne in King's Landing
and you're ruling over
the Seven Kingdoms.
Start the damn joust
before I piss meself!
He's locked in a loveless marriage
and only chose his queen
for her family's name
to hold his kingdom together.
I'm very sympathetic to Cersei.
She was completely in love with him.
She.. she was in awe of him almost,
and he turned into this
almost semi abusive drunk.
Sometimes I don't know
what holds it together.
Our marriage.
This unhappy couple have three
golden haired children to their name
but Cersei keeps a
deadly secret from Robert.
The children are not his.
The truth will be discovered
on a royal trip north
and it's here that our
story really begins.
The King has asked his old
ally Ned Stark to help him rule.
Ned and his wife
Catelyn govern the north.
Fiercely loyal to the crown.
The Starks stand for
loyalty, integrity bravery.
They are really the
moral compass of the show.
They're the good guys
and they're the ones
that you find yourself
rooting for from the start.
The couple have five children:
three sons and two daughters
and the decimation of this happy family
will reverberate throughout our tale.
They're almost too
innocent for that world.
King Robert arrives
with his Queen Cersei
and with them is the
whole Lannister clan.
That's Jamie Lannister.
The Queen's twin brother.
Oh, the Lannisters.
They're blonde they're
beautiful they're arrogant,
so fuck them.
And it's really the Lannisters
who were going to introduce
a lot of trouble into the lives
of the Starks from this point.
The arrival of the
Lannisters into that world
totally sends shock waves
through the whole family.
Bran Stark goes climbing one day,
gets to the top of the tower
and discovers the Lannister's
deepest, dark secret.
The secret is that Cersei the queen
is actually sleeping
with her brother Jaime.
The Lannisters, oh god!
They are..
I have never seen a family.. I
mean talk about dysfunctional.
Stop! Stop.
It's incest which even in
Westeros is generally frowned upon.
It also means that
King Robert's children
are not actually his children.
- It's alright, it's alright.
- He saw us!
I heard you the first time.
He knows what it means
too, and he knows that
if the incest is
discovered, not only will
he and his sister be put to death
but their three children
may very well too.
And so for Jaime Lannister,
the greatest swordsman in Westeros,
there's only one solution.
The things I do for love.
Here's a convenient way.
The kid'll die,
it'll look like he fell
and our kids will be safe.
First in a coma,
Bran will later awake with
no memory of how he fell
or what he saw.
The Royal secret is safe for now
and only the viewer has seen what
the Lannisters will do to keep it.
Everything went pear
shaped after that and really
that's the whole chain
of events starting.
King Robert still wants
Ned down in the capital,
so this will be the last ever time
we see the Stark family all together.
A family which includes
Ned's son out of wedlock,
the bastard Jon Snow.
Ned must now leave his family
and follow King Robert south
taking his daughters
Sansa and Arya with him.
The reason I think that the first
season of Game of Thrones works,
is it's essentially
about this good family
that just wants to
essentially be left alone
and serve their king and their country.
This good family is ripped apart
and thrown into situations
that they never anticipated.
They are bound for the
capital, King's Landing
where Ned's new task will
be to protect King Robert
from those who would unseat him.
And in season one,
viewers learned the greatest
enemies live in exile overseas.
The Targaryens.
They were dethroned by
King Robert in the last war.
The only surviving members of the family
are a brother and sister
called Viserys and Daenerys.
The siblings are the children of
the Mad King who was killed in war.
Viserys dominates his younger sister.
Viserys has more than a
touch of the Targaryen madness
and you know sometimes
he's protecting her
but he's also trying to treat her as a,
- as a bargaining chip.
- Come forward my dear.
In search of an army,
Viserys makes a pact with a
savage tribe, the Dothraki.
Offering his beautiful young sister
in marriage to their leader, Khal Drogo.
She's the only bargaining chip he has;
he doesn't have any wealth
anymore; he doesn't have any armies,
but he has her who he can
trade to this horse lord.
I would let his whole tribe fuck you,
all 40,000 men, and their horses too,
if that's what it took.
He's power-hungry but to a nasty degree.
He doesn't really care
how or by what means,
he just wants to be
important and looked up to.
But his plans backfire.
Daenerys and Khal Drogo fall in love
and become quite the power couple.
Suddenly she finds herself
with Khal Drogo empowered.
People are obeying her.
Tell him I want what was bargained
for or I'm taking you back.
He completely underestimates
not only Danny but Khal Drogo.
What's he saying?
He says yes.
You shall have
a golden crown.
It's a real coming-of-age story
throughout the first season.
She really grows into herself.
- Look away Khaleesi.
- No.
This is one of the turning
points for Daenerys.
I think this is when you realize that
she's prepared to sacrifice
anything for the greater good.
Crown for king.
He was revolting.
He was utterly, utterly revolting,
and that was the moment that she escaped
from her shell. When
she became the woman
and not the kowtowed girl.
And as the Targaryens grow in power,
we learn that King Robert
faces another challenge
to his northernmost borders.
Threats which led past rulers
to build this giant wall of ice
to keep out wild things beyond.
It's protected by the
legendary Night's Watch.
The Night's Watch are a small army
who guard the northern
border of the country.
In season one, there's lots
of fighting for the throne
but actually in the background
there are these creatures
appearing north of the Wall
that nobody has seen
for thousands of years
and no one quite wants to believe
that they're there
but they certainly are.
We hear the characters saying
that this is all folklore
or that this is all made up,
but for the viewer we see that basically
these characters do
exist. They are there.
I think the White Walkers
are really terrifying
mostly because you're not 100% sure,
you know what they're capable of doing
or what their motives are.
They are a serious threat.
In season one, in search of a purpose,
Jon Snow ventures to the Wall
and joins the Night's Watch,
a leader in the making.
Jon Snow's everybody's hero,
Jon Snow's one of my favorite
characters. He's the dude.
He's also in search of answers.
The question of Jon...
Jon Snow's parentage has
been one of the burning topics
amongst not only the show's fans
but book fans for many decades.
Jon Snow is Ned Stark's bastard son.
He brought him back from a war
and we never really
learned who the mother is.
Understandably Catelyn, Ned's wife,
isn't too fond of Jon for that reason.
Try as she may she could
never make peace with that,
with the fact that Ned was, unfaithful.
But down in the capital King's Landing,
Ned Stark has a much
greater challenge to face.
His daughter has fallen
for Prince Joffrey.
She's presented with
marrying the future king,
live in a beautiful
castle, go to banquets,
have beautiful dresses to
wear. A fairy tale story.
Ned has discovered the Queen
and her brother are lovers
and this will be his family's undoing.
When the King returns from his
hunt I'll tell him the truth.
You must be gone by then,
you and your children.
I will not have their blood on my hands.
But before he gets the
chance to talk to King Robert,
King Robert gets himself
killed on a hunting trip.
Joffrey is now king, and
without Robert to protect him
Ned is tried for treason.
He confesses, believing
it will save his daughter,
but misjudges the new ruler.
He's been stuck up in the north too long
and has no idea how
the real world operates,
how to really deal with the kind of...
the politics of Westeros.
Bring me his head!
That's when you realize nobody
is safe in this world at all.
When I saw Sean Bean pushed down
that was the only scene that
really has brought a tear to my eye.
It's cruel, it's heartbreaking,
but there's a point to the
children witnessing this.
If they want to survive they
have to start to be resilient.
They have to learn from this.
It was at that moment you realize
what Game of Thrones was really about.
It's here that the
Stark family splinters.
Arya is whisked away by a Night's
Watch brother loyal to Ned,
leaving Sansa at the mercy of Joffrey.
Robb Stark reacts with murderous rage
to the news that his
father has been beheaded.
Robb's the heir and he's not only
picking up his father's mantle
as Lord of Winterfell,
but he's picking up a much older mantle.
The crown that no one
has worn for 300 years,
the kingdom of the north.
It will lead to all-out war between
the Starks and the Lannisters
who were led by its
patriarch Tywin Lannister.
Tywin Lannister is one
of the great warriors
and battle strategists of the age.
As well as his twins, Cersei and Jaime,
he has a son he despises,
Tyrion, known as the Imp.
You're wounded.
- Good of you to notice.
- Tyrion obviously is just brilliant.
- I hear we won.
- Stereotypes of what
a hero should be or should
look like in Game of Thrones
are just completely
blown out the window,
because we've got Tyrion who, you know,
doesn't look like your
archetypal hero, but he is.
As war rages in Westeros,
over the Narrow Sea,
Daenerys loses a husband
but gains astonishing new powers.
She walks into Khal Drogo's funeral pyre
with fossilized dragon's eggs.
What an epic scene.
Season one ends with
the sight of Daenerys
emerging from a fire, unscathed
with her dragons hatched.
These creatures are
extraordinary creatures
the likes of which have not
been seen in hundreds of years.
'Blood of my blood..'
You see these, these three dragons
around her and you're, just, like,
they're gonna be awesome
when they're grown.
The innocence is gone, she's it.
She's the force now.
As the dragons are born she
comes more and more into her own
- until the power becomes innate to her.
- It's about a new era.
The whole first season is essentially
the old era dying out;
the new era beginning
and by the end she has a sense that
she knows that she's
bound for greatness.
And after the break, watch
those dragons grow in season two.
Welcome back to Game of
Thrones: The Story So Far,
where season two marks
a new reign of tyranny
in the capital, King's Landing.
Joffrey is brutalizing his subjects
as well as his bride-to-be Sansa Stark.
You can't!
What did you say?
Sansa has learned some
painful lessons along the way.
The chivalrous knights
and gallant princes
that she dreamed of, she..
she got a gallant prince
and he turned out to be Joffrey.
Killing you would send
your brother a message.
She's a prisoner in the
worst place imaginable,
enduring all kinds of psychological and
sometimes physical
abuse from these captors.
Leave her face.
I like her pretty.
He's a bully,
and we don't like bullies.
I heard a disgusting
lie about Uncle Jaime.
And you.
He's the product of a
brother and sister shagging,
so like you know this might be
why he isn't all there mentally.
Cersei's smart enough to
realize that Joffrey is
perhaps not what she
might have hoped for
and he's getting out of her control now
and he's a danger in part even to her
and even to other members of the family.
What you just did,
is punishable by death.
Joffrey's enemies are everywhere.
Chief amongst them and just
across the bay at Dragonstone
is Stannis, brother of
the late King Robert,
who believes the throne should be his.
Stannis has learned that Robert's
children are Lannister bastards
which means that it is
Stannis who is next in line.
So Stannis Baratheon, who knows that
King Joffrey is the product of incest,
decides to send ravens out to all
the corners of the Seven Kingdoms
letting them know the Lannister secret.
In order to claim the throne,
Stannis enlists the red
priestess, Melisandre,
who was on her own mission to
find the right ruler for Westeros.
She believes Stannis is the
savior of the world, basically.
He's supposed to be on the Iron Throne
and her magical powers
have no limits, I think.
There's there's so much that
we don't know that she can do.
However, Stannis isn't the
only one after the throne.
His younger brother, Renly
also believes he has a claim
and so war is inevitable.
The Iron Throne is mine by right.
All those that deny that are my foes.
The whole realm denies
it, from Dorne to the Wall.
They both think they should be king
but I'm on Stannis'
side, so screw Renly.
Rather than fight it
out on the battlefield,
Stannis finds another
way to kill his brother.
I guess family ties don't
mean an awful lot in Westeros.
The powerful sorcery of the
red priestess is revealed
when she gives birth
to a sinister weapon.
The shadow baby is basically
just a way to kill Renly
and it comes out of me in a great way.
I think Melisandre, she's
always lived by this religion.
If she's got something
to do she's gonna do it
and she's not gonna let
other people stand in her way.
What I think's brilliant
about Game of Thrones,
he lives in a fantasy world,
it's a completely realistic
depiction of how power works.
What power does to people,
what people do to get power
and what happens when they fall short,
when they miss the mark.
That's why it's so brilliant.
When Renly is murdered, he leaves
behind his widow, Margaery Tyrell
who belongs to the Tyrell family
who are very rich and
powerful in their own right.
Calling yourself king
doesn't make you one
and if Renly wasn't a
king I wasn't a queen.
Margaery is an absolute piece of work.
You know she wants power.
Do you want to be a queen?
No.
I want to be the queen.
Across the Narrow Sea,
Daenerys Targaryen is
learning valuable lessons
in her quest to return to
Westeros and seize the throne.
She's desperate to be a good ruler.
That she can, you know,
go to bed at night saying
I think I'm doing things the right way.
As Daenerys' power
grows, so do her dragons
but as news of their existence spreads,
they become highly sought after.
When she's in Qarth,
everybody's kind of think "Who are you?
We'll just take your dragons.
We'll take your dragons and
you're not powerful anymore."
Dracarys!
People have underestimated
her, the whole way.
And it is in season two,
that we finally see the
dragons kill for Daenerys.
As Daenerys gets stronger in exile,
Jon Snow and the Night's Watch
are on a mission beyond the Wall
where the true scale of the
threat to the kingdom is revealed.
... Blown the horn. When will he come?
The army of the dead is on its way
and it's gonna kick off sooner or later
and really you know they've
got to get out of there
- as fast as they possibly can.
- One blast for friends,
two for foes.
And three for White Walkers.
The threat of winter
coming is very much a myth
to the people of the south.
They're not really taking it seriously.
They don't know about the undead and
all the horrors that
are coming towards them.
So what we learn in season two
is that the White Walkers
are very much real.
They're nothing like we've
ever seen before in television.
They're not just zombies, they're
not just statues, they're walking...
ice cubes, basically.
They're, they're really bad
and they're, really scary
and it's literally, I think it's
got to be a fight of Ice and Fire.
We have all these kingdoms
wanting to fight for the throne
and they think that that is what
ultimately the battle is about
but really at the end of
the day, they're not looking
at what's the real problem
here and it's the White Walkers.
And it's in season
two in King's Landing,
where we see that Tyrion may
just be an asset to the war
when Stannis launches
an attack on the city.
I'll lead the attack!
Battle of Blackwater was his moment.
He was the best person to speak
to the people of King's Landing
and to get them to protect
their, their.. their.. their city
because he knows what
it's like to fight,
he knows what it's like to have
your back up against the wall.
Those are brave men
knocking at our door.
Let's go kill them!
Tyrion manages to get
the troops fired up
by giving a good speech and
fired up then heads out with
them to fight Stannis on the bay.
He doesn't last very long,
he gets knocked out
after a couple of minutes.
Tyrion is upstaged by his father Tywin
who arrives with his own massive
army bolstered by the Tyrells
who've now firmly joined the cause.
It's that moment where you really see
where power lies.
It's not in the king,
it's in the person behind the king.
The battle is over.
We have won!
And so season 2 ends with
the Lannisters victorious.
After the break, season 3 brings
more terrible losses for the Starks
when they attend a cataclysmic wedding.
Welcome back to The Story So Far.
Where as season three begins,
Daenerys has set sail on a mission.
She and her dragons may have
grown in power and stature
but securing an army still eludes her.
So she ventures to a place
where she can buy one.
She knows she needs an
army, a powerful army too,
if she ever wants to
reclaim the Westerosi throne
and the best bet for
that are the Unsullied.
I have dragons.
- I'll give you one.
- She appears to want to trade
the dragon for slaves.
She seems to have made
this daft agreement
to give away her best dragon.
She hands over the dragon.
Next thing you know once she's
got control of the Unsullied...
_
Then it's very easy to say to the dragon
who still will listen
to her and not to him,
- burn him.
- Dracarys!
Because you would take power if
you have the force of a dragon.
They're pretty impressive creatures.
She's been the mother of dragons
and knew she was destined for greatness
but now she really is
a queen with an army.
To then see that she
has thousands of people
on her team and then you
get like this swoop past.
She's got these, like
fire-breathing mythical creatures
that are just gonna tear shit up.
As this young Targaryen gains followers,
in King's Landing a young
Tyrell is gaining influence.
Margaery has replaced Sansa
in Joffrey's affections,
a reward for her family's
military support at Blackwater.
I imagine it must be so exciting
to squeeze your finger here and
watch something die over there.
Marjorie is a woman
who's on top of the game,
she's controlling where she's going,
she's a proper feminist icon.
But the Tyrell's ambitions
are not going down well
with Cersei Lannister.
Alana is a matriarch of the family
and she advises her granddaughter
on how best to play the political game
so that she might take
power in King's Landing.
To make matters worse,
her soul mate Jaime
is a prisoner of war.
He is held first by Brienne of Tarth,
then both are captured
by a northern faction.
Looks like your woman's
getting the better of you.
This is all bundled up in
when Jaime begins to start
thinking about other people.
His efforts to stop Brienne being raped
are the beginning of that.
You know who she is, don't you?
It's good when those little
bits of goodness come in those
characters that are so devilish,
as well just give you
a little light in there.
Lord Selwyn would pay his
daughter's weight  in sapphires
if she's returned to him.
I mean of course it being Game of
Thrones it doesn't get him anywhere.
Another one of those
Game of Thrones moments
which has so much more going on in it
than just him losing his hand.
He's the greatest swordsman
in Westeros we're told,
so he can't do that anymore.
He's now made a good friend in her
and he's seen a lot of things and
I'm sure he's questioning what
being a Lannister is about as well.
Yet without his hand,
we see Jaime Lannister
at his most heroic.
The heartless knight who
pushed Bran Stark from the tower
finds new honor in Season 3.
He's left, he's left her behind,
he's abandoned her
and he's on his way to
King's Landing and then,
then his captors mentioned that,
what's gonna happen to her.
Nice bear!
And then he decides
to return and save her.
And it is in season three that
we witness the fearsome work
of another powerful
family, the Bolton's,
who are scheming to take
control of the north.
I think the Bolton's want pretty
much what everyone else seems to want.
It's power and status.
Kill me!
You're no good to me dead.
We need you.
Ramsay, a bastard son of the family,
enjoys torturing his enemies
including Theon Greyjoy
who he took prisoner when sacking
Winterfell after Ned's demise.
Historically, the Bolton's
have always been just...
just under the Starks,
kind of the Starks
have always been on
top of them, so I think
they feel that now
is their time to rise.
You don't look like a
Theon Greyjoy anymore.
It's unbelievable what Ramsay
is capable of doing to people.
Reek!
He's just all about the mind,
he's all about making
you doubt yourself,
he's all about getting in
there and making you insecure
and making you feel like you
can't go up against him.
Another hostage at large in season three
is Arya Stark, kidnapped by the Hound.
The disgraced knight
plans to find Arya's family
and trade her for cash.
Remember what happens
to children who run.
One of the great double
acts of Game of Thrones
is the Hound and Arya.
Don't!
- Don't kill him.
- There's something so
perversely magical about that pairing,
sort of warped mentor-protégé
relationship that develops.
In his desire to claim a ransom,
the Hound heads for the Twins
where he knows Arya's
mother and brother,
Catelyn and Robb Stark,
are attending a wedding.
The Twins is a strategic river crossing
controlled by the Frey family
and the Starks need them
onside for their war effort.
Walder Frey is a very
bitter nasty old man
who controls a small but
significant area in the kingdom.
I was pledged to marry one
of you and I broke that vow.
If he's been let down by Robb Stark
after this promise,
if he shows any kind of forgiveness
or, just let it go, we didn't
want to marry my daughters,
marry someone else, he would lose face,
in that world, it's a vicious
world he's operating in.
The Stark family offer
Robb's uncle to make amends
and are here for that wedding,
a terrible mistake.
Catelyn in her heart
knew that you do not break a promise
if you are the king of the north
and also you certainly don't
break it to Walder Frey.
Your grace...
He's probably laid awake for nights
just planning it and
timing it and working out
just how it's gonna work out.
The moment when Cat sees that
Roose Bolton is wearing chainmail
is a powerful moment.
Why would you wear
chain mail to a wedding,
and what is the purpose of chain mail,
it's to prevent you getting killed.
- Robb!
- Even though I'd read the scripts,
the Red Wedding still completely,
was shocking and I was
still screaming at the TV,
"Don't do it, no don't, don't",
you just don't want it to happen.
The Red Wedding is the event that
pretty much decimates an entire
generation of the Stark family.
Within the Game of Thrones,
Walder Frey's not playing
the Game of Thrones.
He's not attempting to be the king.
He's actually perfectly
happy with what he's got.
He has his own little fiefdom
and he's all sitting in the
chair watching terrible things.
He's a rotter isn't he.
He's absolutely rotten.
Grim.
The Lannisters send their regards.
It is an ambush backed
by Tywin Lannister.
Robb was such an amazing character
and you kind of want him to be the king
and to win.
It's the cruelty of it
and it's the relishing of it.
Everything goes to
hell at the Red Wedding.
Arya stark arrives at the Twins
to witness her brother's desecrated body
and loses any last shred of innocence.
She's there. She's there at
the Red Wedding, she's outside
and she was so close,
you know she was so close to
seeing them again, she was so close.
The path that she goes on,
she learns to become stronger and fight
and also she is after revenge.
And when she comes across
her family's killers later...
You little shit.
... she matches their brutality.
She's had to go over to the dark side,
that's what makes her interesting.
In order to survive in that world,
you've got to match what is given you.
And so by the end of season 3,
all the elder Starks have
gone from the Game of Thrones.
Only the children remain,
orphaned and scattered across Westeros,
including Bran Stark, still
paralyzed from his fall.
He's fled Winterfell with a loyal
band of followers heading north.
So Hodor we know as
- a very loyal character.
- It's all right, Hodor.
He lost the use of his legs
and Hodor's the person that
carries him around and
takes him everywhere.
Being the big giant of a man that he is.
It's all right.
The wolves will protect him.
Him and his brother
Rickon are the two last
male heirs to, to the,
to the Stark household
and yet it's fast depleting.
We're running out of Starks.
Bran Stark is very
much on his own journey
to discover the roots
of this ancient magic
that's reappearing in the
kingdom throughout the seasons.
And yet amid this loss
comes a small victory.
Unlikely hero Samwell Tarly
stumbles on a weakness
of the White Walkers.
Samwell reaches for all he has to hand,
an old dragonglass spear
he once found in the ground.
To his astonishment it, it works.
The spells are shattered
and it's melting before him.
And stay with us to see wedded
bliss vanish, after the break.
He's choking!
Welcome back to Game of
Thrones: The Story So Far.
We're in season four, a Royal
Wedding in King's Landing
unites two great houses of Westeros,
the Tyrells and the Lannisters.
Margaery and Joffrey's wedding
is one of those weddings
that we all have to go to where
there's no love in the room.
The wedding brings another
great family into the game.
The Martel's, represented
by Prince Oberyn.
We're the hottest couple at the wedding
What else is there to say?
- Ellaria Sand.
- My lord. My lady.
- Charming.
- He has a zest for life,
and all the beautiful things
that the world has to offer.
None of it is as
beautiful as his own rage
and taste for revenge.
Oberyn is seeking vengeance
for his sister's brutal death
- at the hands of the Lannisters.
- Rape and murder
of women and children is
considered distasteful.
Joffrey really uses
the wedding as an excuse
- to be as horrible as he can.
- Uncle,
he can be my cup bearer.
He sees it as an opportunity to
wield his power because he can.
And you're dying for
something to happen to him.
And so an unseen hand
poisons the newly wed King.
- Idiots, help your king.
- Move away!
It's the moment of retribution
that the whole of the Seven Kingdoms
- have been waiting for.
- Geoffrey!
I think everybody who
watches Game of Thrones
was hoping this day would come.
I wanted to kill him in such a way
that the viewers were
reminded that here's a
13 year old boy who's dying.
Though it is actually the Tyrells
that have poisoned Joffrey,
it is Tyrion who is blamed.
This is really the point
where Tyrion's fragile bonds
with his family begin to unravel.
Take him!
Take Him!
In plot terms, the death of Joffrey
is another shaking of the board
where the pieces are scattered
and also it's one of those things that
elevate the whole series from
merely a story into a saga.
As the royal family grows weaker,
news from Westeros reaches Meereen
where Daenerys has conquered the city,
but she is not yet ready to
capitalize on her enemy's weakness.
King Joffrey Baratheon is dead.
Murdered at his own wedding.
This would appear to
be a really good time
for her to finally make her
play for the Iron Throne.
She has the dragons
and she has the army,
and she has the strength of character.
But actually she has
new responsibilities now,
when she has unfinished
business where she is,
and she's still trying
to learn how to rule.
And to compound matters,
her dragons have grown so big
that Daenerys has started
to lose control of them.
No!
As they get bigger,
as her power increases,
the harder it is for her to manage.
And that's where the
story then has to go.
All they're going to
bring is complexity.
And when one of the dragons
kills a child and abandons her,
Daenerys is left with no other choice
but to chain the other two.
She's just locked up her dragons, so
can she unleash them again,
and will they forgive her?
Without the mighty force of her dragons,
Daenerys is faced with a dilemma
as to what to do next.
She's definitely going through a sort of
a dark night of the soul, I think,
where she's trying to determine,
have I got what it takes.
And so in season four, as
Daenerys remains in exile,
across the Narrow Sea,
Sansa Stark has fled the capital
and taken refuge with her aunt Lysa,
who has been seduced by an arch schemer.
Littlefinger is playing
a very chaotic game
and he thrives on that.
Oh, my sweet wife.
For Littlefinger, it's all
about getting power I think,
and using Lysa as a pawn along the way.
Sansa has witnessed Lysa's murder,
and covers for Littlefinger.
Sansa's one of these
pure characters who's been
mistreated all through the series.
She's seen a lot of horrible,
horrible things happen
and she's never been
able to take control
and this is the first time. Actually,
she's got nothing else to lose.
When Sansa lied
to protect Littlefinger, I
cheered. I thought thank God girl.
He tried to reason with her,
promised her she was the only
one he'd ever loved but...
she stepped through those doors..
What you discover, is that she's
been learning this entire time.
She's been listening,
she's been watching.
She's been taking
Littlefinger's lessons to heart.
So from one Stark protégé to another,
Sansa's sister Arya is
still the Hound's hostage
but they're now on an equal footing.
Who would pass the bloody gate?
The bloody Hound, Sandor Clegane.
He's her captor but
he's also her protector
and you know she's seen his own pain
and his own fear at times and
they've shared some
dangerous situations.
But when The Hound is
gravely injured in battle,
Arya is forced to strike out on her own.
Fuck it. I'm ready.
Now he's wounded and he's dying
and she's remembering
all he said about mercy
and he's asking for mercy
and by mercy he means, you
know, a quick thrust to kill him.
And she doesn't give it to him.
Kill me.
She won't put him out of his misery,
she won't give him the easy way out,
she's going to leave
him there to suffer.
Another wandering Stark is
Arya's crippled brother, Bran,
who has made it north of the Wall
in search of the three-eyed Raven
who he believes will
help him walk again.
All the time aided by his loyal
traveling companion, Hodor.
I think Hodor's more
than just Bran's legs.
I think he means a lot to
Bran, you know, someone...
he's always been there through
absolutely everything, you know,
even though he can't speak,
he can only say one word,
he's always someone
that's looking after them.
You know, in a world of evil,
he's probably one of the only good ones.
Clearly Bran is very
important because he's trekked
all the way up north to a
cave where this, this raven
has been summoning him for
the past couple of seasons, and
now he's in this cave
with the three-eyed raven.
Really we're gonna find out
what, what the grand scheme
of things is for Bran.
You'll never walk again.
But you will fly.
His powers, he's getting
stronger and there's gonna be some
really exciting things happening
and we're gonna find out
more and more about him.
At the Wall, the Night's Watch suffers
a huge wildling attack at Castle Black,
but in season four they
get a powerful new ally.
Stannis Baratheon, who's
been away licking his wounds
after the Blackwater defeat,
joins them with his vast army.
The Battle of the Blackwater was a huge
and crushing defeat at
the end of season two
and it's taken them
basically two seasons
to sort of rebuild from that,
and his arrival means that
Jon Snow could have a new ally
in the battle against the
White Walkers beyond the Wall.
If my father had seen
the things that I've seen,
he'd also tell you to burn
the dead before nightfall.
All of them.
Season four draws to a mighty
climax in King's Landing
when the ultimate father-and-son
showdown comes to a head.
Tyrion is tried for murder.
I'm guilty... of being a dwarf.
- You're not on trial for being a dwarf.
- Oh, yes I am.
I've been on trial for
that my entire life.
He's put on trial for a
murder he doesn't commit.
His father deserts him and betrays him.
I demand a trial by combat!
I mean, trial by combat,
you can get someone
to fight for your honor, so
whether you're wrong or not,
as long as they win the
fight that's what matters.
He names Oberyn Martell as his champion.
The one thing that he's ever lived for,
is to avenge his sister's death
and he knows that now that the
opportunity is presenting itself,
there is no question that
he will get what he wants.
You killed her children!
And he does get what he wants by
forcing a confession out of him.
It's not exactly how he expected it.
I killed her children.
He still technically got
what he wanted, you know.
Then I raped her.
Then I smashed her head in like this!
But when Oberyn is defeated,
Tyrion is sentenced to death.
In Westeros the pursuit of justice is
as futile as anything else.
Oh, get on with it, you son of a whore.
Is that any way to
speak about our mother?
Tyrion is released from
jail by his brother Jaime
and told to go and board
a ship and run away.
Instead he decides to
check in on his father.
But it's his former lover Shae
that he discovers in Tywin's bed.
Tyrion then kills Shae in
a sort of fit of jealousy
and then takes a crossbow
and goes to find his father.
Tyrion.
Put down the crossbow.
It's so tightly wound, this scene.
This is someone who spent his whole life
trying to win his approbation,
as much as he hated him,
he really wanted that, you know.
Obviously that's never gonna happen now
because he put a crossbow
bolt in his groin.
What it means, is when a
big character like that goes,
there's gonna be a power
vacuum and there's gonna be
hustling and jostling
to get into his place.
I am the queen!
I am the queen! Have you lost your mind?
Join us after the break,
we're in season five
and new power rises in King's Landing.
Welcome back to the Story So Far.
Where in season five, a Royal
Wedding unsettles Cersei.
Her son Tommen is now king
and has fallen under the spell
of his new Queen, Margaery,
much to Cersei's dismay.
When Margaery come in his life,
I think he was just
enjoying life so much.
Judging from the King's enthusiasm,
the Queen Mother will be
a queen grandmother soon.
- Wouldn't that be a lovely day.
- Him being King
was just a whole new
excitement, a whole new life.
Cersei empowers religious fanatics
to help her topple her
rival, Queen Margaery.
You can't do this. I am The Queen!
She brings back the faith
militant because she's, like, well
hopefully I can clear
the board with these guys
and regain some of my power.
But Cersei's engineered
her own downfall.
Royalty is no longer above the law
and fanatics come for her next.
There's another contender to power
in Westeros and it's... it's religion.
It's the power of the faith.
They want to remove all the excesses,
to strip Cersei of all her finery,
and encourage her, in inverted commas,
to become clean.
A sinner comes before you.
Watching Cersei do the
walk of atonement...
something happened that I
thought would never happen
and that is I felt compassion.
No matter what she'd done previously,
she didn't deserve this.
And so season 5 sees her left naked
before her subjects to
atone for her infidelities.
The walk of shame was tough
was very, very tough for her.
Very, very few women could
have done what she did,
complete that walk.
And you see her
trying to maintain this regal presence
but she can't.
Stripped down to her literally,
physically and emotionally
and psychologically
stripped down to her most vulnerable,
and then swept up into the
arms of the Beast that she,
that she invited into the world.
The strange creation
that is her new knight.
It's just a brilliant twist.
Also getting a new ally
in season five is Daenerys,
in the form of Tyrion.
After killing his father, he's
fled across the Narrow Sea,
a fugitive on the run.
He was a Lannister
and he had all the money in the world
and a noble name and a big bag of gold
can buy you a lot. All that's gone now.
He's totally at the mercy of
the people he's traveling with.
- Who're you?
- And then the unthinkable happens.
- I am the gift.
- He's captured and handed over
to his family's greatest enemy,
the Targaryen Queen
in Waiting, Daenerys.
My name is Tyrion Lannister.
And between them they are
an extraordinary force.
Protect your queen!
She appoints him as
her political adviser
but when a civil rebellion begins,
Tyrion gets to witness Daenerys
transform into a true Targaryen.
The symbol of the Targaryen's
coming to claim their power
is on the back of a dragon. 'Cos I mean,
it's not much you can do
when you're standing on the ground
and a dragon's coming at you.
She's had the dragons
now for quite a long time
but her actually
becoming a dragon rider,
that's her claiming her birthright
more than I think anything
else we've seen her do because
that is how the Targaryan's
wielded their power.
Vlar!
Everybody painted that
picture of Daenerys
flying her dragon, had
never really happened,
and I've waited so
many years to see that
and she finally does and
she does it in a wicked way
where she's escaping death.
Daenerys, she's got
the greatest name ever.
Stormborn, Mother of Dragons.
Daenerys Stormborn
Targaryen, I love that name.
She's got these dragons as backup
and then she's got Tyrion,
who knows King's Landing,
who knows the political side of things,
and he's been through battles as well.
Yet as season five ends,
Daenerys' dragon delivers
her to an uncertain fate.
The last thing we see of
Daenerys in season five,
she's surrounded by Dothraki,
back where she bloody started.
In season five is one
of vengeance for Arya.
The young Stark follows
her mentor to Braavos
- to become an assassin.
- To serve well,
a girl must become no-one.
Arya's relationship with
Jaqen is fascinating.
He is utterly mysterious
and she is seduced by his power.
I didn't come here to sweep floors.
No?
Why come then?
- You said I could be your apprentice.
- The power of death,
the power to choose who dies.
And Arya uses her new skills
to slaughter Meryn Trant,
a name on her kill list of
people who've destroyed her world.
Arya, I think has crossed a line,
and if you look back to season one,
what would Ned Stark
think of Arya's actions.
Is that what he would
want for his daughter?
There is a sense of vengeance
rather than a sense of justice.
As Arya explores vengeance,
back home the battle is on
for the Stark family home.
Stannis Baratheon is
marching on Winterfell,
now held by the Bolton's.
But sometimes sacrifices must
be made to ensure victory.
He's going after something and it is,
it's increasingly futile.
In a desperate move,
Stannis follows the
advice of the red priestess
who promises him victory
if he makes an unspeakable
offering to the Lord of Light.
She managed to convince him
to burn his own daughter.
That's one of the most chilling
scenes, I think, of season five,
when, when he burns his child.
She's believed in this god
for so many years I think that
if it's not to do with
the god she kind of just
blocks everything out
and I think that's what
happened as she blocked out
the fact that she was going
to be sacrificing a child.
She was sacrificing the King's blood.
Melisandre really thought
that Stannis would be the one
and you know she's put a
lot of her heart and soul
and everything else
into, into helping him.
But it proves to be his undoing.
His men desert him,
and Melisandre, realizing all is lost,
- flees to Castle Black,
- Your Grace.
leaving Stannis to advance
to Winterfell on his own.
Speak up.
Can't be worse than mutiny.
He's had a rough old
time, Stannis, hasn't he.
Because really he
should be the king from
after Robert Baratheon dies,
but every battle he loses he becomes
further and further involved
with this kind of fantasy.
And awaiting Stannis at Winterfell
are the Bolton's who tried to
cement their position in the north
with a tactical marriage to Sansa Stark,
orchestrated by master
manipulator Petyr Baelish.
She shouldn't trust Littlefinger,
I mean why are you gonna trust
Littlefinger, I mean, geez!
He is the dodgy car
salesman in Game of Thrones,
offers you everything
and gives you nothing.
May I introduce my son,
Ramsay Bolton.
Now that the Bolton's have kind of
established themselves at Winterfell,
bringing in a Stark will really
solidify their position in the north.
But it's a huge miscalculation
that traps her in another
brutal relationship.
Ramsay is a horrible, cruel,
evil, power-hungry man.
He took psychotic
nature to another level.
I mean he went there, and he went some.
Oh, no no no.
You stay here Reek.
You watch.
Fellow-prisoner Theon Greyjoy
aka Reek is too terrified to help.
I think we all thought he should
have stepped in on the wedding night.
Let's be frank.
With Ramsay distracted by battle,
- You're leaving it to me?
- Sansa is caught attempting to escape,
and it's only then that
Reek finds the courage
to become Theon again.
Stop! Stop!
I think that was a moment
that we all needed to see,
Theon again had been so
much at the mercy of Ramsey,
that finally he had a moment
where he could do good.
And so by the end of season five,
Sansa has jumped either to
her death or to her freedom.
It's someone
being pushed in every
way to the absolute limit
of their will to live and
having come through that,
she's obviously gonna be
quite a different person.
As Sansa and Theon leap
from the walls of Winterfell,
nearby Stannis is facing
defeat by the vast Bolton army.
I think Stannis had given up.
I think even before
they'd gone into battle,
I think he was going there to die.
Fate finally catches up with Stannis
when he comes face-to-face
with Brienne of Tarth
who sought vengeance for
Renly's death since season two.
She is probably the
toughest person going about,
about Westeros.
But as Stannis bows out,
Jon Snow comes up against a greater foe
when he ventures to Hardhome
to make peace with the Wildlings.
This alliance is sacrilege,
but when the White Walkers
launch a full attack,
Jon sees his hunch is right.
All humans must unite to fight them.
What's so great about the
whole White Walker mythology
is the way it has been
building throughout the series.
Who knows what they
want. They would bring
death and destruction
to absolutely everything.
Up until this point they've been
semi-mythical characters. It's been
the White Walkers in those cold lands
that no one ever goes to
and here they are in
front of the heroes,
then they're very real
and it's a very real danger.
I don't think the White
Walkers are afraid of anything.
I think fear is just
not in their vocabulary.
And then Jon and the
viewers see the Night's King
reveal that he has a greater power.
He can raise and recruit the dead.
It's a challenge to Jon,
and 'look what I can do'.
Forget all the other
battles that are going on,
you know, battles for castles
and, and kingship, you know,
he's got to focus his army.
But on Jon's return to Castle Black
in the final minutes of season 5,
viewers witness the cruelest blow of all
in a gut churning finale.
When I saw the cross with traitor
written on it, I thought oh
no, they're not gonna kill him
and then they did!
For the Watch.
You root for him
but the great thing
about Game of Thrones
is your heroes can die any second.
For The Watch.
They're all members of
the Night's Watch and
no matter what one of
their brothers has done,
what they did was
worse than what he did.
And so season 5 ends
on betrayal and death.
Is this really the end for Jon Snow?
Only season six holds the
answer, after the break.
Welcome back to the Story So Far,
where season six begins
at the scene of a crime.
Jon snow lies slain at Castle Black
and all hopes are pinned
on the red priestess
and her magic to bring him back.
Game of Thrones needs Jon Snow.
We do, we need him to
finish what he started.
As viewers hope for Jon's resurrection,
we learn that Melisandre
harbors a great secret.
The reveal of ancient Melisandre
was definitely one of the
most stunning surprises
in season six of Game of Thrones.
It shows how much older she actually is
and how much longer she's
been believing in this god for.
Then we see her use this power for Jon.
She tries to bring him back to us,
to resurrect him, it doesn't work.
When the wolf started to sort of
make some noise that's when I thought,
I think everyone thought,
Jon Snow's alive.
And then he's just
like that moment of...
Jon Snow has returned and
all the Westeros rejoices.
And after the miracle of Jon's rebirth,
comes a partial reunion
of scattered Starks
when Sansa arrives at Castle Black,
and together they'll gather forces
in a bid to retake the north.
Sansa's become majestic but
she's also become savvy.
She's lost that naivety.
A monster has taken our home
and our brother.
We have to go back to
Winterfell and save them both.
She's a queen, really.
In terms of being from a powerful family
and being able to make decisions
and tell other people to do stuff,
I think she's gonna tell
other people to do stuff.
And across the sea in season six,
another young royal's in similar mood.
Daenerys,
who's been a hostage of the Dothraki,
burns their leaders
and converts the tribe.
The huge Dothraki horde.
_
We're gonna finally get a lot of
different power factions coming together
in a very scary explosive way.
And she also gets a navy,
forging an alliance with
the Ironborn who bring ships.
But as Great Houses unite for war,
beyond the Wall we learn
more about the deathly foe
which threatens them all.
While time training
with a three-eyed Raven,
Bran Stark uncovers a great secret.
White Walkers were
created from the first men.
The children of forest
invented the White Walkers to help
protect their own race.
It was an innocent defense
to do that.
But clearly it has gone out of control.
And when the White
Walkers come for Bran,
there are terrible casualties.
Hodor is a goner.
Hold the door!
A completely pure act of protection.
There was nothing,
there was no greater goal
to what he did
other than protect Bran.
Everyone who's basically just given
in order to give way for Bran and
there must be a reason, right?
We know he's become
the three-eyed Raven.
But how's he going to use those powers.
And as the three-eyed Raven,
Bran resolves a great Stark secret
when he sees Jon Snow's mother
is Ned's sister, Lyanna.
You understand what Ned has been
going through the whole time.
He made out that it was
his son, his bastard son,
but it was really his nephew.
But it confirms Jon
Snow is still half Stark
and in season six,
he and Sansa march on their
family seat of Winterfell
to fight Ramsay Bolton,
in what goes down in history
as the Battle of the Bastards.
Ramsay's now top dog,
having murdered his
father and newborn brother.
Now, if you want to save...
You're going to die
tomorrow, Lord Bolton.
When you play the Game of Thrones,
you either win or you die,
you know, and she knows
it's about winning now;
she's had enough of all
the rest; it's time to win.
She offers her insight.
You think he's going to fall
into your trap, he won't.
He's the one who lays traps.
She's lived with this man for
a long time and she knows that,
he is cruel to the core.
- Sansa's words go unheeded.
- Let's play a game.
Ramsay baits Jon with
his hostage Rickon.
Run to your brother.
It shows a lot about
how Ramsay's mind works.
He's calculating; he's always
thinking about the next move,
you know it's very interesting how
Machiavellian he can be as well.
Ramsay Bolton's, like, yes
I've got you now boy,
just in the middle of no man's land.
That's what Game of Thrones
does so brilliantly is, it,
it's constantly pitting good
moral forces against bad ones,
and you don't just win
because you're good.
They were surrounded by the entire army;
they were being driven into the mud.
Ramsay should have won, he was much
more conniving, much more cunning,
and if it hadn't have been for
Sansa coming in at the last minute,
then he probably would have won.
Now that Sansa has brought the cavalry,
the Knights of the Vale,
it's a done deal that
the Starks are going home.
This was probably the first
major victory in, in six years.
They're suddenly inside the castle.
Winterfell.
It seems Jon will kill Ramsay,
but he then leaves
Sansa to take the scalp.
There was only one way to kill him
and Sansa found the right way to do it.
She knows what she's gonna do, and
she knows he deserves it.
All memory of you will disappear.
If you were face to
face with your nemesis
and you had the opportunity,
you'd take it.
She's hardcore.
She has the makings of a Cersei.
But it's Jon Snow who becomes
king as the season ends
with the Starks controlling the north
and for now Sansa is by his side.
She's a character that
will surprise people
because she's not what she seems.
And neither is Sansa's sister Arya.
Blinded and stabbed in her
training as a faceless man
she's now back in Westeros
to deal with Walder Frey.
She's gone on this mad journey.
Arya comes in disguise,
having chopped up Walder's sons.
They weren't easy to carve.
She wanted him to see who she was.
The face comes off and there's a knife.
The last thing you're ever going to see
is a Stark smiling
down at you as you die.
She's been caught up in it so young
that she's turning
into this child soldier.
Revenge is a dish best taken cold.
I literally cannot wait now
for her and Cersei to face off.
In fact Cersei elevates revenge
to an art form in season six
as the Lannisters fight for
their family's very survival.
These royal lovers are united in grief
after the Sand Snakes
killed their daughter.
The Lannisters are all about power.
They're all about revenge.
We're the only ones who matter,
the only ones in this world,
and everything they've taken from us
we're going to take back and more.
It doesn't matter how long it takes,
they will get you back.
With Jamie sent away to fight revolt,
Cersei is left alone to face
judgment by the faith militant.
We are told that Cersei is
going to turn up for a trial but
we know perfectly well
she's not going to.
But it's now she plays
a game-changing hand.
She was always going to
have a dastardly plan.
The man who was sent by Cersei
to hold Tommen in that room...
There's something wrong.
Marjorie knows what's up in an instant.
The High Scept is packed with
those who've wronged Cersei.
The Tyrells, High Sparrow
and faith militant.
The amazing thing about Game of Thrones
is the spectacle is always incredible
and you never know it's coming.
This isn't gonna end well.
Cersei has, of course,
unleashed wildfire.
She's wiped out this fantastic building;
she's destroyed all her enemies.
That's what makes Cersei so brilliant;
she's been to the absolute lowest place
that you could possibly go
and she still comes out on top.
In the moment where she gets her
revenge on everyone else, she loses
the only thing that she has
left that matters to her.
Knowing that his mum's the one that's
pretty much murdered his wife,
what has he got to live for.
Tommen's death leaves
the Iron Throne empty,
so a new reign begins.
A witch told her that she,
she was cursed and that all
of her children would die.
It didn't stop her from loving her kids
and trying to protect them at any cost,
but she accepts very swiftly her fate.
And so Jamie returns
to a new world order,
courtesy of his sister.
She's devastated the Tyrells.
Now the Lannisters are once
more a force to be reckoned with.
Queen Cersei, sitting
on the Iron Throne.
I think it's good to
see her on the throne,
because it really has been
her who's been pushing the men,
and so she should be there,
right there or wrongly.
As one Queen takes the throne,
another sets sail to
challenge her for it.
Finally Daenerys, the Targaryen Queen
is on her way to Westeros,
with a vast alliance she
spent six seasons amassing.
We're now getting to crunch time.
As she comes to conquer,
the burning question for season seven:
who might join her now?
Absolutely everybody against the
Lannisters, everyone against Cersei.
Like, Cersei doesn't have a chance.
But they'll fuck with us.
I do have this theory
that the White Walkers
will sit on the Iron Throne.
Just leave those dragons alone.
- Synced and corrected by chamallow -
- www.addic7ed.com -